practiceaptitudetests.com 2016-05-29

# Practice Aptitude Tests | FREE Online Aptitude Tests | Privacy Policy - Practice Aptitude Tests | FREE Online Aptitude Tests

**Privacy Policy**

Practice Aptitude Tests Limited ("We, Us, Our") are committed to protecting and respecting the privacy of you (“You”, “Your”) as a user of this website [www.practiceaptitudetests.com](http://www.practiceaptitudetests.com/) (“Site”).

This policy (together with Our website terms of use ([above)](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Fr27cvcsOUE2xWywngz1NJJN1TrKwv4cSOjgWmJkPQo/edit#heading=h.gjdgxs) and Cookie Policy ([below)](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Fr27cvcsOUE2xWywngz1NJJN1TrKwv4cSOjgWmJkPQo/edit#heading=h.nmf14n) set out the basis on which any personal data We collect from You, or that You provide to Us, will be processed by Us. Please read the following carefully to understand Our views and practices regarding Your personal data and how We will treat it.

Information collected: We may collect and process the following personal data about You:

  * Information that You provide by filling in forms on this Site. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use this Site, subscribing to Our services/products, posting material or requesting further services/products. We may also ask You for information when You report a problem with Our site;

  * If You contact Us, We may keep a record of that correspondence;

  * We may also ask You to complete surveys that We use for research purposes, although You do not have to respond to them; and

  * Details of Your visits to our Site and the resources that You access.

Please note that We outsource payment processing and all transaction handling to PayPal Services, please therefore refer to Paypal’s own User Agreement and Privacy Policy. We do not store any bank card details nor do We share customer bank details with any third parties save where We are compelled to do so (see [disclosure ](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Fr27cvcsOUE2xWywngz1NJJN1TrKwv4cSOjgWmJkPQo/edit#heading=h.28h4qwu)below).

IP addresses: We may collect information about Your computer, including where available Your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to Our advertisers. This is statistical data about Our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

Cookies: Our website uses cookies to distinguish You from other users of the Site. This helps Us to provide You with a good experience when You browse the Site and also allows Us to improve our Site. For detailed information on the cookies We use and the purposes for which We use them see Our [Cookie Policy ](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Fr27cvcsOUE2xWywngz1NJJN1TrKwv4cSOjgWmJkPQo/edit#heading=h.nmf14n)(below).

Storing your personal data: By submitting Your personal data You agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that Your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Where We have given You (or where You have chosen) a password which enables You to access certain parts of Our Site, You are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask You not to share a password with anyone.

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although We will do our best to protect Your personal data, We cannot guarantee the security of Your data transmitted to the Site; any transmission is at Your own risk.

Use of your personal data: We use personal data held about You to:

  * To ensure that content from Our Site is presented in the most effective manner for You and for Your computer;

  * To provide You with information, products or services that You request from Us or which We feel may interest You, where You have consented to be contacted for such purposes;

  * To allow You to participate in interactive features of our service, when You choose to do so;

  * To notify You about changes to Our service; and

  * To provide You with after sales support.

We may also use Your data, or permit selected third parties to use Your data, to provide You with information about goods and services which may be of interest to You and We or they may contact You about these by post or telephone if You have consented to this.

If you are an existing customer, We will only contact you by electronic means e-mail with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to You.

If You are a new customer, and where We permit selected third parties to use Your data, We (or they) will contact You by electronic means only if You have consented to this.

If You do not want us to use Your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box when subscribing to Our Site.

Disclosure: We may disclose your personal data to third parties if We are under a duty to disclose or share Your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply Our website terms of use (above) and other agreements.

We may also disclose Your personal data to third parties:

  * In the event that We sell or buy any business or assets, in which case We may disclose Your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

  * If Practice Aptitude Tests Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

Your rights: You have the right to ask Us not to process Your personal data. You can exercise this right at any time by contacting Us at “[webmaster@practiceaptitudetests.com](mailto:webmaster@practiceaptitudetests.com)” or by using the contact form at “[www.practiceaptitudetests.com/contact/](http://www.practiceaptitudetests.com/contact/)”.

Links: Links to other websites from this Site are provided for Your information only, and do not imply Our endorsement or affiliation with the providers of those websites. We have no control over the privacy policies of those websites, accept no responsibility for them, and We disclaim liability for any loss or damage that may arise from Your use of them.

Changes to our Privacy Policy: Any changes We may make to Our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page from time to time and without notice to You.

Contact: Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy should be addressed to [webmaster@practiceaptitudetests.com](mailto:webmaster@practiceaptitudetests.com)

**Cookie Policy**

Introduction: In addition to any information that You choose to submit to Us, We or selected third parties may use a variety of technologies that store or access information already stored on Your personal computer, laptop, tablet or mobile phone (each a device) whenever You visit or interact with Our Site.

Cookies: a cookie is a text file placed on a device when a user visits a website. Cookies can be temporary (eg session) or permanent (eg persistent). They can also be first party (eg placed by us) or third party (eg placed by a third party advertiser or advertisements server). Further details on the cookies used on this Site and their purposes are set out below.

This Site may use cookies of the following types:

  * Single session cookie: enables this Site to keep track of Your movement from page to page in order to ensure that You will not be asked for the same information that You have given on a previous visit to the Site. We may use the cookie to enable You to return to a previous page, or analyse user behaviour, such as which pages You have visited during Your visit in order to improve Your overall experience and the performance of this Site.

  * Remember me cookie: enables this Site to remember Your personal preferences such as login details in order to improve user experience for example by avoiding You having to re-enter these details on each visit to the Site.

  * Global Session cookie: enables Us to collect information such as number of visitors to this Site, links clicked on, from what links You used to come to this Site and pages visited in order to analyse user behaviour. This information is collected in an anonymous form and will be collated with similar information received from other users to enable us to compile reports in order to develop and improve user experience by displaying more tailored and relevant content for example. We might use these cookies to highlight articles, services available within this Site or adverts that we believe may be of interest to You.

  * Flash cookies: a Flash cookie (or locally shared object) is a data file placed on Your device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or downloaded by You to Your device. This can operate across all Your browsers.

  * HTML5: HTML5 cookies can be programmed through HTML5 local storage and do not require a plug-in.

The single session and global session cookies are provided on Our behalf by a trusted third party service provider, Google Inc, to aid with reporting of user behaviour, market research, providing targeted advertisements and improving Site functionality for example. This user behaviour is analysed in order to improve this Site. The information collected is not linked to personal data. To see how this applies to Google Analytics, visit <http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html>. You can stop tracking by Google Analytics by visiting <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB>.

Cookie duration: The single session cookie is a temporary cookie which remains in the cookie file of Your browser until You close the browser. The other cookies will remain in the cookie file of Your browser after the closing of the browser, and will become active again when You reopen this Site. The different cookies have different expiration dates. Following expiry of a cookie, a new version of that cookie will be downloaded when You next visit this Site, unless You have withdrawn Your consent in the meantime.

Refusing cookies: We obtain Your consent to Our information collection technologies by providing You with transparent information in Our Cookie Policy and providing you with the opportunity to make Your choice. You do not have to accept cookies, but without accepting them You may experience reduced Site functionality. If You wish to reject the cookies then please read the information that came with Your browser software to see how You can turn off the automatic download feature.

For more information about cookies, including how to set Your internet browser to reject cookies, please go to [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
